二零二一年。
中考英语真题听力特快专题吉林卷。
一情景反应，根据听到的句子选择恰当的应答语。
1. Good morning, Bob.
Good morning, Bob.
2. Paul, don't eat in
Paul, don't eat in
3. I'm going to take an English exam.
I'm going to take an English exam.
4. Nice to meet you, Sally.
Nice to meet you, Sally.
5. Sorry, I took your pen by mistake.
Sorry, I took your pen by mistake.
对话问答，根据听到的对话及问题。
6. Tom, Mr.
is leaving. Let's have a goodbye party for him.
That's a good idea.
Tom, Mr. Brown is leaving.
Let's have a goodbye party for him.
That's a good idea.
Question. What kind of party will they have?
7. Alice, you don't look well.
What's wrong with you?
I have a toothache.
Alice, you don't look well.
What's wrong with you?
I have a toothache.
What's the matter with Alice?
8. Hi, Frank.
What's your favorite subject?
English. I practice it every day.
Hi, Frank. What's your favorite subject?
Question. What's Frank's favorite subject?
9. Ben, I finished reading the book Journey to the West.
Great. I've already read it too.
It's the most wonderful book I've ever read.
Ben, I finished reading the book Journey to the West.
Great. I've already read it too.
It's the most wonderful book I've ever read.
Question. What does the man think of the book?
10. I heard you went to Dalien last week.
Yes. I had an enjoyable train ride.
I heard you went to Dalien last week.
Question. How did the man go to Dalien?
三、图片理解：看图听描述，选择与听到。
的描述内容相符合的选项。
下列图中有一幅图片与描述内容无关。
11. There is a beautiful giraffe in the
There is a beautiful giraffe in the zoo.
12. The window of the bedroom is The window of the bedroom is
13. Our teacher Miss Goh is having her class now.
Our teacher Miss Goh is having her class now.
14. Look, this pair of shoes is fit for me.
Look, this pair of shoes is fit for me.
15. Football has already become a popular sport in the world.
has already become a popular sport in the world.
四短。
文理解：根据听到的短文内容，完成人物与对应信息的匹配。
It's a Sunday morning.
My family are all at home.
Cindy is my sister.
She loves reading very much and now she is reading a storybook.
My little brother, Mike, is only 5 years old.
He is so cute and often runs here and there.
Now he is playing with our pet dog.
Can you see that tall and strong man?
He is my father Steve.
He is good at almost everything.
At this moment, he is washing his car in the garden.
Where is my mother, Helen?
She is busy cooking in the kitchen.
Though she is tired, she loves making nice food for us.
My name is Peter.
I am a top student at school and sometimes I feel stressed out.
Now I am listening to light music in order to relax myself.
It's a Sunday morning.
My family are all at home.
Cindy is my sister.
She loves reading very much and now she is reading a storybook.
My little brother, Mike, is only 5 years old.
He is so cute and often runs here and there.
Now he is playing with our pet dog.
Can you see that tall and strong man?
He is my father Steve.
He is good at almost everything.
At this moment, he is washing his car in the garden.
Where is my mother, Helen?
She is busy cooking in the kitchen.
Though she is tired, she loves making nice food for us.
My name is Peter.
I am a top student at school and sometimes I feel stressed out.
Now I am listening to light music in order to relax myself.
morning. My family are is only He
听力测试到此结束。